<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 02:16:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my first blog post, and
I’m sure I’ll write a lot more interesting things in the future, for now, I will share a little about…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post, and
I’m sure I’ll write a lot more interesting things in the future, for now, I will share a little about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I am going to skip my childhood and plan to circle back to that when I am ready to talk about mental health and the impacts it has on people in the field of STEM, but for now we will start in college. I went to SUNY Delhi in 2009 where I purist and received a Associated of Applied Sciences in Veterinary Technology.  Growing up, I always dreamt of becoming a veterinarian and this was my first step in doing so. Along the way I learned that medicine wasn’t for me, and seeing sick animals was emotionally too challenging, especially when it came to euthanasia, so I went back to school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing that I want to help still, I decided to try working with people and eventually got by BA in Human Services. After a few months as a case manager, I decided to go back to school to earn my Master’s of Social Work to open opportunities in the field. With a BA, I was limited to what tasks and services I could perform and a master’s degree also increased my salary by about 10,000 a year (which isn’t much but the issues in the field of human services are for another time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 10 years I have worked from a direct care worker for people with development disabilities, a case manager for individual with sever mental illness and homelessness, a therapist for foster children, a behavioral therapist for children who have autism spectrum disorder and more. Over the years I became overworked, burnt out, underpaid but still found myself wanting to make a different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020 when covid-19 hit, it changed everything for everyone. For me, I became a “front-line hero” providing in-person therapy for children in foster care. During this time, I was not only working with children who had their lives changed by going remote, to foster parents who didn’t know how to provide support during this time and it felt like regulations were changing daily. I eventually became burnt out and decided to take matters into my own hand.
I could not go back to college as my student loans were already more that I would like them to be, so I knew I needed to either build on a skill I had or teach myself a skill. I looked at a few different career switches from HR to assistant positions and more but found myself reading articles about people teaching themselves how to code and breaking into tech. I never thought that this was a choice for me. I was never given computer classes to take, I wasn’t good at math so I assumed I wouldn’t be good in any tech field and I didn’t even know how the internet worked, let along being able to build something- but I tried anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 6 months I learned how the internet worked, I learned what programming was, I learned about languages and the difference between front-end and back-end and then I picked a language and began learning. I chose python and started taking free youtube courses, started a couple udemy courses, worked on freecodecamp.org and anywhere else I could get information. I coded everyday eventually was able to teach myself enough to get admitted into HackBright Academy- an all-women full stack bootcamp based in California. I am currently in the part time cohort that began 7/2021 and ends 1/2022.  I have learned so much (including Python, JS, React, SQL, Flask and more) and it’s actually crazy to think that I am completing this in only 7 more weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a really crazy ride and I am hoping to review some of my journey, post some things that I have learned, my commentary on some issues I have seen and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will also be lots of photos of my dog.
But that feels like a good place to start, but we have some catching up to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>